A Guide to the Leitch Family Papers, 1806-1858
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Leitch Family Papers, 1806-1858
The Library of Virginia
23579
47 leaves, negative photostats
Leitch Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying, 18 August 1950, by George H. S. King, Fredericksburg, Virginia.
Biographical Information
The Leitch family resided in Stafford County, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1806-1858, of the Leitch family of Stafford County, Virginia, containing deeds, 1814-1858, for land in Stafford County to and from members of the Leitch family and others; plats, 1825-1848, of property in Stafford County; an agreement, 20 June 1806, between Henry Fitzhugh of Stafford County and Henry Fitzhugh of King George County, Virginia, on the one part, and Benjamin Leitch on the other part to sell lands in Stafford County; power of attorney, dated 15 December 1818, from George Leitch, et. al. to Abner Leitch of Fredericksburg, Virginia; and maps of the Hartwood tract, Hollywood, and Snowden, all in Stafford County.
Contents List
- Agreement, 20 June 1806, between Henry Fitzhugh of Stafford County and Henry Fitzhugh of King George County, Virginia, on the one part, and Benjamin Leitch on the other part to sell lands in Stafford County.
- Deed, dated and recorded 14 June 1814, for 127 acres from William Leitch of Spotsylvania County, Virginia, to Sally Leitch, et. al. of Stafford County, also includes a survey of the tract, dated 26 May 1814.
- Power of attorney, 15 December 1818, from George Leitch, et. al. to Abner Leitch of Fredericksburg, Virginia.
- Deed, dated 1 November 1819 and recorded 10 April 1820, for 1/4th part of 127 acres from Abner Leitch, acting attorney, to James P. Rowe of Stafford County.
- plat, 5 November 1825, for 49 acres belonging to Charles Bruce, includes metes and bounds of 49 acres deeded from Henry B. Sthreshley to Charles Bruce, 18 October 1828.
- Deed, dated 18 May 1826 and recorded 5 September 1826, for all rights in a tract of land from Sally Leitch et. al. to James P. Rowe.
- Plat, 15 September 1826, of 423 acres belonging to Henry B. Sthreshley.
- Deed, dated 31 October 1833 and recorded 10 March 1834, for 272 acres from Charles and Sarah Bruce to James S. Jarrell, all of Stafford County.
- Deed, dated 16 June 1835 and recorded 4 July 1865, for 109 acres from Abner and Sarah Leitch to Samuel O. Monteith of Stafford County.
- Deed, dated 5 February 1842 and recorded 14 February 1842, for 109 acres from Samuel O. and Milly Monteith to Elizabeth Ball of Stafford County.
- Deed, dated 6 April 1844 and recorded 12 April 1844, for 4 acres from James and Susan Chinn of Stafford County to James S. Jarrell.
- Deed, dated 1 January 1845 and recorded 11 March 1845, for 10 acres from Charles S. and Frances Scott of Stafford County to James S. Jarrell.
- Plat, 24 October 1848, for 98 acres belonging to William Lee of King George County.
- Deed, dated 31 January 1849 and recorded 11 May 1849, for 98 acres from Elizabeth Ball to William Lee.
- Deed, dated 15 March 1853 and recorded 24 March 1853, from Richard and Sarah Berrey to James S. Jarrell for all rights to the real estate of Richard Berrey, deceased.
- Deed, dated 14 May 1853 and recorded 26 May 1853, from Catherine Berrey to James S. Jarrell for all rights to the real estate of Richard Berrey, deceased.
- Deed, dated 2 December 1853 and recorded 6 December 1853, from Elizabeth Gollahorne to James S. Jarrell for all rights to the real estate of Richard Berrey, deceased.
- Deed, dated 23 January 1854 and recorded 27 May 1854, for 102 acres from Thomas and Fanny (Fannie) Purkins to William Lee.
- Deed, dated 25 December 1855 and recorded 24 March 1856, for 288 acres from James S. and Rachel Jarrell to Mordecai J. Gayle.
- Deed, dated 11 February 1856 and recorded 24 March 1856, for 60 acres in from William J. Snelling, et. al. to Mordecai J. Gayle.
- Deed, dated 5 July 1856 and recorded 14 July 1856, for two tracts of land from Mordecai J. and Virginia Gayle to Absalom P. Rowe.
- Deed, dated 1 November 1856 and recorded 9 February 1857, for all right to estate purchased of Richard Berrey, et. al. from James S. and Rachel Jarrell to Absalom P. Rowe.
- Deed, dated 27 March 1858 and recorded 11 May 1858, for 50 acres from Jemima Berry to James R. Gollahorn.
- map, no date, of the Hartwood tract in Stafford County.
- Map, no date, of Hollywood and Snowden in Stafford County.